# SAUMIL SHAH

MUMBAI, INDIA 400016 | 8788912711 | saumillinux@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I am software developer who is interested in compilers, OS and similar low level stuff, also interested in backend development and lots of reverse engineering.

I have worked on several exciting industry projects from scratch and always excited to discuss and learn new stuff.

## **SKILLS**

- Progrmaming languages : C/C++, Java,
  Python, Javascript.
- Testing

• Reverse Engineering

- Web development
- RDBMS Development and SQL

## **EXPERIENCE**

## 07/2022 - 02/2023

## **Backend Developer Intern**

# **VENTURA SECURITIES** - MUMBAI, INDIA

- Wrote reusable, testable and efficient code using Python.
- Coded, tested and developed solutions in alignment with project requirements.
- Setup graylog logging.
- Created and maintained data pipelines and sync jobs.

#### 02/2022 - 07/2022

#### WEB DEVELOPER

#### **GEEKRIDER** - MUMBAI, INDIA

- Built layouts according to customer parameters using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Designed websites, portals and large-scale web applications for multiple clients.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.

## 10/2021 - 02/2022

## Java Developer

## PRIMELEAF CONSULTING - MUMBAI, INDIA

- Optimized software applications to reduce processing, storage and network usage needs.
- Updated and removed legacy java dependencies and code.
- Added new features according to business needs.
- Examined and removed high severity bugs and exploits.

## 08/2021 - 11/2021

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER

## SAKURA BIOTECH - MUMBAI, INDIA

- $\bullet \quad$  Brought mock-ups to life with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Improved and designed new layouts to achieve usability and performance objectives.

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

08/2022 DIPLOMA IN CS: COMPUTER SCIENCE

VIDYALANKAR POLYTECHNIC - MUMBAI

04/2019 SSC

SARASWATI MANDIR HIGH SCHOOL - MUMBAI

# **LANGUAGES**